buseireann.ie 2008-12-17

# Privacy Statement - Travel anywhere in Ireland by bus or coach with Bus Éireann e.g. Dublin, Cork, Galway, etc.

  1. CIÉ respects your privacy
  2. Sites covered by this Privacy Statement
  3. Links to non-CIÉ websites
  4. Types of information we collect
    1. Personal Information
    2. Non-personal information
  5. Children's privacy
  6. CIÉ's use of cookies
  7. How CIÉ uses your information
  8. Who CIÉ shares your information with
  9. Your choices
  10. Your privacy preference and opting out
  11. Access to and accuracy of your information
  12. Keeping your information secure
  13. Changes to this statement
  14. Contacting us

## CIÉ respects your privacy

The CIÉ Group of Companies respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it. CIÉ provides this Privacy Statement to inform you of its Privacy Policy and practices and of the choices you can make about the way your information is collected online and how that information is used. We've structured our websites so that, in general, you can visit CIÉ on the Web without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information. We make this notice readily available on our home page and at the bottom of every CIÉ Web page.

Return to the top

## Sites covered by this Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement applies to all CIÉ Group of Companies owned websites and domains, and our wholly owned subsidiaries i.e. Bus Éireann - Irish Bus, Bus Átha Cliath - Dublin Bus, CIÉ Tours International and Iarnród Éireann - Irish Rail.

Return to the top

## Links to non-CIÉ websites

The CIÉ websites may provide links to third-party websites for your convenience and information. CIÉ is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites or for the privacy policies and practices of other third parties.

Return to the top

## Types of information we collect

**Personal Information**  
This is Information that is associated with your name or personal identity. CIÉ uses personal information to understand better your needs and interests and to provide you with better service. Once you choose to provide us with personal information, you can be assured it will be used only to support your relationship with CIÉ. We take seriously the trust you place in us. CIÉ will not sell, rent or lease your personal information to others.

On some CIÉ websites, you can order products or services, request information, subscribe to marketing or support materials, register yourself, or apply for a job at CIÉ. The types of personal information you provide to us on these pages may include name, postal address, phone number, e-mail address, user IDs and passwords, billing and transaction information, credit card information, contact preferences, educational and employment background and job interest data.

To personalize our websites, services or communications and improve our products and services, we may also ask you to provide us with information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, and experiences with our products or services. Providing this additional information is optional.

**Non-personal Information**  
This is data about usage and service operation that is not associated with a specific personal identity. CIÉ collects and analyzes non-personal information to evaluate how visitors use the CIÉ websites.

Non-personal data we collect may include the pages visited on the CIÉ websites, unique URLs* visited within the CIÉ websites, browser type, IP** address and date/time patterns of visits. Most non-personal data is collected via cookies or other analysis technologies. CIÉ Web pages use cookies. To learn more, read CIÉ's use of cookies.

Return to the top

## Children's privacy

CIÉ is committed to protecting the privacy needs of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children's online activities and interests. CIÉ does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 and CIÉ does not target its websites to children under 13.

Return to the top

## CIÉ's use of cookies

Cookies are small text files that a website can use in order to recognise visitors who revisit a site so as to facilitate their ongoing access to and use of the site. It enables usage behaviour to be tracked and aggregate data to be compiled that would facilitate more targeted advertising and improved content. Typically, cookies involve the assigning of a unique number to the visitor. One simple way to prevent the use of cookies it to activate the facility which is available in most web browsers that enables the user to deny or accept cookies. However, visitors should realise that certain cookies may be necessary in order to provide the visitor with certain features such as the customised delivery of certain information.

Return to the top

## How CIÉ uses your information

CIÉ uses your personal information to provide you with products or services and to help us better understand your needs and interests. Specifically, we use your information to help you complete a transaction or order, to communicate with you, to provide service and support, to update you on services and benefits, to personalize promotional offers and to personalize some CIÉ websites. Occasionally we may also use your information to contact you for market research regarding CIÉ products or services. We will give you the opportunity to choose your privacy preferences regarding such communications.

Credit card information is used only for payment processing and fraud prevention. Credit card information and sensitive personal data are not used for any other purpose by our financial services providers or CIÉ and will not be kept longer than necessary for providing the services, unless you ask us to retain your credit card information for future purchases.

Personal data given to CIÉ may be transferred across state and country borders for the purposes of data consolidation, storage and simplified customer information management. Whenever your personal information or financial information is transferred across state and country borders CIÉ will ensure that the information is transferred in accordance with this Privacy Policy and as permitted by the [Data Protection Acts of Ireland](http://www.dataprivacy.ie/).

Non-personal data is aggregated for reporting about CIÉ website usability, performance and effectiveness. It is used to improve the customer experience, usability and website content.

Return to the top

## Who CIÉ shares your information with

CIÉ will not sell, rent or lease your personal information to others. CIÉ will not share your personal information with third parties except in responding to your requests for products or services. Your permission will be requested when you submit your information. CIÉ may share customer information across CIÉ-owned business entities and companies working on our behalf.

CIÉ contracts with third-party service providers and suppliers to deliver complete products and services. Suppliers and service providers are required to keep confidential the information received on behalf of CIÉ and may not use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for CIÉ. These service providers may change or we may contract with additional service providers to better accommodate our customers. CIÉ will not share personal information with any other third parties without your permission, unless required by law enforcement action, subpoena, or local law.

If a third party serves on CIÉ a subpoena or other lawful document compelling disclosure of your identity, CIÉ will use its best efforts to provide you notice to the latest address in our files. CIÉ is not responsible if your contact information is not current or if CIÉ is otherwise unable to provide notice.

Return to the top

## Your choices

CIÉ gives you the choice of receiving a variety of information that complements our products and services. You can subscribe to receive certain product and service specific information and CIÉ-wide marketing communications. CIÉ-wide communications may include new product information, special offers, or an invitation to participate in market research. We give you a choice regarding delivery of CIÉ-wide communications by postal mail, e-mail and telephone. We will make every effort to honour your preferences. This option does not apply to communications for the purpose of administering order completion.

Return to the top

## Your privacy preference and opting out

Examples of unrelated uses include sending communications about special offers, product information, and marketing messages. You can, however, choose to receive these types of communications by following the instructions at the time of entering your personal data ("opt-in").

To opt-out of receiving communications you have expressly requested (such as e-mail newsletters, software updates, etc.), use any of the following methods:

  * Select the e-mail "opt-out" or "unsubscribe" link, or follow the opt-out instructions included in each subscription communication
  * Return to the Web page(s) where you originally registered your preferences and follow the opt-out instructions
  * Write to the CIÉ Webmaster - be sure to provide your name, e-mail and postal address, and relevant information about your CIÉ registrations.

Return to the top

## Access to and accuracy of your information

CIÉ strives to keep your personal information accurate. We have implemented technology, management processes and policies to maintain customer data accuracy. We will provide you with access to your information, including making reasonable effort to provide you with online access and the opportunity to change your information. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity, such as a password and user ID, before granting access to your data. Certain areas of CIÉ websites may limit access to specific individuals through the use of passwords and other personal identifiers.

Return to the top

## Keeping your information secure

CIÉ is committed to protecting the information you provide. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, and to ensure the appropriate use of the information, CIÉ has in place appropriate physical and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect.

When you purchase travel tickets online or access your personal profile you can do so through a secure server. The use of SSL technology means that all personal information, such as your credit/debit card number, will be encrypted as it travels from your computer to the CIÉ Online Booking Engine. When received, the information is decrypted and processed in the same way as a normal card transaction by telephone. This security measure is working when you see either the symbol of an unbroken key or closed lock (depending on your browser) on the bottom of your browser window.

If your browser supports SSL, and if you entered our site via our secure server access, then transmission of any sensitive data will be protected. If your browser does not support SSL, we recommend that you upgrade to the latest version of any browser to enhance the security of further transactions, otherwise the transmission of your personal data may not be protected and CIÉ disclaims any responsibility in this regard.

Return to the top

## Changes to this statement

If there are updates to the terms of CIÉ's Privacy Statement, we will post those changes and update the revision date in this document, so you will always know what information we collect online, how we use it, and what choices you have.

Return to the top

## Contacting us

CIÉ values your opinions. If you have comments or questions about our Privacy Policy, please send them to the CIÉ Webmaster or write to us at the following address:

CIÉ Webmaster  
Córas Iompair Éireann  
Heuston Station  
Dublin 7  
Ireland 

Or alternatively by email.

Revision: October 2004

*URL is the global address of documents and other resources on the World Wide Web. For example, http://www.CIE.ie is the URL for CIÉ's home page.

**An IP address is an identifier for a computer or device on a TCP/IP network, such as the World Wide Web. Networks use the TCP/IP protocol to route information based on the IP address of the destination. In other words, an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web, allowing Web servers to locate and identify your computer. Computers require IP addresses in order for users to communicate on the Internet, browse and shop.

Return to the top
